ASHUTOSH **DEVKOTA**

ashutosh.devkota@gmail.com · 818-288-3344 <u>https://github.com/adevkota</u> https://adevkota.me/

Full stack software developer. Experienced in Angular, React, Node, Express, JavaScript, HTML, CSS. Currently also learning Ruby/RoR via The Odin Project, and open to learning any languages/frameworks as needed. Experience working with nearshore resources.

EXPERIENCE

JULY 2017 - PRESENT

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, PAMPERED CHEF

Over my time at Pampered Chef, I have been part of the KPI team at Pampered Chef. Our goal has been to make it easy for a consultant to run their business on a phone. I have architected, designed and developed solutions to meet business goal in time and in budget. I have also mentored junior developers on all things front end as well as JavaScript in general.

- Full stack JavaScript experience.
- Designed and developed Consultant Product Catalog, a React PWA that can be used completely offline. Business had a need to make our product catalog available to consultants when they did not have network connection. We delivered a solution that uses React, service workers, indexed DB, node/express and S3. Once installed, the app lets users browse or search for our entire catalog even when they are offline. We also built a server-side application that the web app can talk to in order to check for updates to the data or requesting new data that was deployed to EC2. (This project combined with the mobile friendly cart below will also allow us to completely sunset the native mobile app we still maintain saving business an estimated 2 million dollars in maintenance cost.)
- Converted existing party cart into a mobile friendly version with close collaboration with UX and PO. Business wanted consultants to be able to use the party cart in their mobile devices as a stopgap measure until we release a new, fully mobile first party cart. I was able to work with our PO one-on-one and deliver a solution in about 6 weeks (end to end). I re-wrote the CSS, and updated HTML where needed without changing any of the underlying logic of the current cart, confirmation and summary pages that was written in Hybris.
- Drove the development and adoption of consultant's corner an angular SPA that uses modular build and route based lazy loading. UX and business wanted one seamless experience for consultants regardless of what tool they use within the PC ecosystem. I designed a lazy-loaded, modular, component driven angular application. I also developed the initial application and once we had our team's

pieces running smoothly, other teams also started adopting this project. Currently, all 5 engineering teams are contributing to this project in some capacity. We also adopted a feature-flags and trunk-based branching. All these decisions were made to save business money by cutting down on the engineering time and effort to build, deploy, maintain each page as its own application while giving each team the freedom to develop at their own pace and priority.

Developed various server-side node/express apps to support client-side
applications. We are adopting the client-server architecture, which means that all
of our new web applications communicate with one or more node applications.
These applications are written in typescript, node/express, and related libraries.
The interaction between the applications mostly follow REST pattern using
HTTP(S), but we are also currently developing one major application that uses web
sockets along with HTTP(S). For our server-side applications, we mostly use
Jasmine and Karma for unit testing.

Tech: AWS, mongo dB, Git, Angular (8), React/Redux, service-workers, Indexed DB, node/express, typescript, Jasmine, Jest, Protractor, Cucumber, and related libraries.

AUGUST 2015 - JULY 2017

SENIOR UI DEVELOPER, RR DONNELLY

Worked on RRD Care, a project primarily targeted towards healthcare companies to help them with proofing and collaboration, and visibility to orders in production.

- Responsible for building parts of and maintaining the RRD Care application using AngularJS, D3, Karma, Mocha, Chai, and Sinon.
- Increased the code coverage to above 75%, advocated git best practices, implemented and maintained a living style guide.

Tech: AngularJS, Jasmine, Protractor, Gulp, Mocha, Chai, Sinon, Karma, ES6, Git

JANUARY 2014 - MAY 2015

UI DEVELOPER, FOLLETT SOFTWARE

Worked extensively with AngularJS in multiple projects, including implementation of eBook and Audiobook reader, admin panel and library home pages.

Tech: AngularJS, Jasmine, Protractor, Karma, SVN

JULY 2012 - JANUARY 2014

UI PROGRAMMER, ALCHEMY COMMUNICATIONS INC

Responsible for website user interface development, Developed the presentation layer using HTML5 and CSS per internal standards and guidelines, including client-side validation and client-server communication using JSON over HTTP

EDUCATION

DECEMBER 2019

MASTER OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE, GEORGIA TECH

Graduated with a GPA of 4.0

JUNE 2012

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, COMPUTER SCIENCE, UC SAN DIEGO

SKILLS

- React, Redux, and related ecosystem
- JavaScript/ES6
- Html/Html5
- Jasmine/Chai/Mocha/Karma/Jest
- Also familiar with python, Java, C#

- Angular
- Node/express
- CSS/Sass
- Protractor/Cucumber